

ABOUT ME

After higher school, I decided to join the hotel industry as a waiter, that was the last job my father would like me to do as he wanted me to work rather in the government sector in India.

8 years plus later I amstill in this hospitality sector and proud to say I am a hotelier.

My specialties are managing large volume restaurants, fine dining restaurants, room service, banquets and bars operations.

I am very lucky to part of brands like Hiltons, Radisson, ITC to live and understand all these

international chains culture (WE ARE HILTON WE ARE HOSPITALIY, EVERY MOMENT MATTERS, MAKE

IT RIGTH, YES I CAN, etc.....) which was very helpful in building me a

Manager.

I have a passion for this industry and I am proud to say I am an hotelier.

Lading by examples, driving the business, Taking risk, collaborating with other colleagues, Problem solving, Growing, Developing & Retaining talents, and A YES I CAN attitude are my key strength. e



AMAN KUMAR BAR OPERATION MANAGER

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Phone No: (OMAN) +968 79048691

• Email: aman.singh@bartender.net

• Birthday: 5th February 1989

• Nationality: Indian

LinkedIn profile: <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/r.amansingh</u>

• Languages Spoken: English, Hindi – (Intermediate)

Arabic (Beginner)

Driving License: Private Car (India)

Address: Sohar, Al Batinah, PO Box – 662, Sultanate of Oman

WORKING EXPERIENCE

August 2016 – UNTILL NOW Bar Manager

RADISSON HOTEL GROUP

Radisson Blu – Oman

Responsibilities

- Running the best bar in the town called Aqua
- Aqua 121 Covers
- Amaranthai Speciality Thai Restaurant
- Pool Bar
- Mini Bar
- Al Khaimah Shisha Lounge
- Day to day operations and administrations tasks. Working in close collaboration with other departments in driving F&D revenue, social media exposure and quest satisfaction.
- Making sure the team always delivered the YES I CAN attitude and service to our guest through our company belief - Every Moment Matters by doing weekly and monthly internal trainings.
- Monthly event and promotions in food and beverage.
- Food and Beverage meu planning and reconciliations.
- Guest data and feedback for the future business.

NOVEMBER 2016 – August 2017 F&B Supervisor Acting Assist Restaurant Manger

Radisson Blu Sohar -Oman



Responsibilities

- Running the day to day operations of F&D Department Overlooking:
- Al Zafaran All Day Dining 250 Covers
- Amaranthai Speciality Thai Restaurant
- Room Service
- Mini Bar
- Al Zafaran Lobby Lounge
- Buffet Layout and planning for the weekend as well as Brunch Operation.



Hilton Al Hamra Golf and Beach Resort RAK, Bar Superv

NOVEMBER 2013 – AUGUST 2016



Achievement

- Was Personal Butler in charge for Qatar football president H.E Ahmed Al Thani.
- Lead The service of Sheik of RAK and **Oman Culture** Minister.
- Was acting as the number 2 in Line.
 - **Blue Energy** Chairperson for our hotel since January 2014.
 - **Involved** in Budgeting, Forecasting, FF&E & **CAPEX**
- Festivity and theme party planner and In charge.
- Nominated for Young F&B Leader award in 2019 from management in Hotel and Catering News Middle East Magazine.

Responsibilities

- Supervising the Day to Day Operations with The Help of Outlet Manager.
- Implementing The Standards According to The Standard Operating Procedure Lay Down By The Organizations.
- Supervising the Inventory for Wine Cellar, Bar & Humidor.
- Supervising the Inventory for Kitchen Stewarding.
- Supervising the Daily Maintenance of Outlet with The Co-Ordination of Engineering.
- Meeting The Budget for The Day and Month
- Making the Duty Roaster.
- Taking Training Class for Waiters and Bartenders
- Informing quest about daily specials or promotions.
- Dealing with The Resident or Non-Resident Guest for Their Requirements, Taking and Fixing Up Groups Reservations, Fixing Menus for Them
- Handling Social networking.
- Handling the biggest beach brunch of the town.
- Was Responsible for VIP cocktails as well as Destination wedding cocktail Parties.

Hilton Al Hamra Golf and Beach Resort RAK, U.A.E Food & **Beverage Supervisor**



Responsibilities

- I was managing the Mai Tai Lounge Which Known for its own cocktails and food..
- Most of the CEOs and MDs of RAK Free Zone companies were our regular

Radisson Noida India F&B Captain December-2010 to REGRADISSON



October-2013

Responsibilities

- Preparing the duty roster and meeting the daily/ monthly budgets.
- Dealing with the resident & non-resident guest managing group reservations and Finalizing the menu.
- Managing the duties within restaurant area in accordance with health, hygiene and Safety regulations.
- Ensuring profitability of operations and supervising all aspects of restaurant including Menu- planning.
- Production to ensure compliance with quality & hygiene standards.
- Receive guest payments and process transactions



- Participated in
 Bacardi Cocktail
 Program
- Awarded 3 Time
 Bravo Certificate in
 Radisson Noida
- Selected 4 Time Best
 Up sellers Of The
 Month
- Selected More than 6 times for **Star Bond**.
- Highest Achiever outlet representative.
- Certified PDR/PDP
 Trainer
- **OEX** Champion.
- Completed HACCP training from UAE government.



EDUCATION

- Pursuing Business and Strategic Management From EMAS Russia.
- 3 years Degree in Hotel Management from I.H.M. Meerut (2006-09)
- Intermediate from B.S.I.C PATNA
- High School from B.S.E.B PATNA

PRO SKILLS

- Team Leadership
- Staff Development
- Highly Motivated
- Goal Oriented
- Dedicated & Committed
- Employee Motivation & Proactive
- Restaurant ,Bars, Banqueting ,Theme planner Operations specialist
- Deadlines, Creative, Success
- Computer Skills-Word, Excel, Power point, Micros, Opera, Symphony, FMC, Birch street,

Mr. Omer Ozcan General Manager Radisson Blu Hotel Istanbul Omer.ozcan@radissonblu.com Mr. Raphael Rodrigues Director Food & Beverage Holiday Inn Dhaka City Centre Raphael.Rodrigues@ihg.com